DANIEL CORREA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

8	Colombia
	+ (57) 3127693402
\subseteq	danielc.web@gmail.com
in	www.linkedin.com/in/danielcb29
3	danielcb29.github.io Q github.com/danielcb29

Software Engineer with 2+ years in software development focused on FrontEnd programming, Service Oriented Architectures, and algorithms design. Challenge driven, always willing to learn, passionate about implementing new technologies and writing code.

EXPERIENCE

UI Software Engineer

PSL-International / Medellín, Colombia

Jan 2017 - Jun 2017

- Project GTL Tablet Management: Inmates tablets configuration management, command and control functionality
- Scrum software Methodology
- AngularJS (Typescript, Grunt, Karma, Jasmine, Requirejs) / Bootstrap based UI

Software Developer

Cedeosft (Univalle) / Cali, Colombia

Feb 2015 - Dec 2016

- Project "SIND Coldeportes", a SaaS application to handle Colombian sport information.
- Agile and Extreme Programming (XP) Software Methodology
- Django + Bootstrap + Django rest framework + Ionic
- PostgreSQL Multi-tenant database.

EDUCATION

B.Sc Computer Science

Universidad del Valle / Cali, Colombia

Feb 2012 - Jun 2017

- Awarded Academic Scholarships for being at the top of the class.
- Computer Science Study Center (CENESIS) coordinator for student events from 2013 to 2015.
- Teaching assistant of Algorithms and Programming, Discrete Math, Introduction to IT and Calculus I courses from 2012 to 2014

B.Sc Computer Science

Universidad de Extremadura / Cáceres, Spain

Sep 2015 - Jul 2016

- One year Interchange Scholarship.
- . SOA, Data Mining, IoT with Arduino, Search (Elasticsearch, Crawler Design), AngularJS and other courses
- HackForGood 2016 participation (MBA scholarship on UPM University postulation)

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

- Programming Languages: Python (Django), Java, C++, Scheme, Ruby, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Front-end Programming: Angular, AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Bootstrap, Ionic
- Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL. Elasticsearch for indexing and information retrieval.
- DevOps: Docker, Heroku, AWS, Jenkins.
- Source Control: Git, GitHub, BitBucket
- Languages: Spanish (Native), English fluent

- Daniel Correa Web Page (2017): Personal web page,
 Angular 4+, Bootstrap => https://danielcb29.github.io/
- Form Project (2017): Angular Medellín open source project, Angular 4+, NodeJS, MailChimp => https://github.com/angular-medellin/form
- Movie Cli (2016): Final project of Alert Logic Angularjs certification course, Angular2 client of TMDB API => https://danielcb29.github.io/Movie-Cli/
- SIND Coldeportes (2015): Project to handle all Colombian sport information. SaaS Architecture. Django + Angularjs